A grimoire by Flamme the Legendary Mage?
They say books attributed
to Flamme are never real.
Only forgeries have been found until now.
This is probably the best imitation
I've seen so far, though.
Not bad as a reward for defeating monsters.
I really don't understand the appeal.
That said, when all you see are fakes,
you start to doubt whether the
genuine article ever existed at all.
Flamme, the founder of humanity's magic,
is like a fairy tale herself.
A fairy tale, huh?
I suppose. It's been long enough since then.
I'm probably the only one
who remembers her face.
It's morning.
Ms. Frieren woke up early!
Is that so impressive?
Of course it is.
We must be sure to praise her.
What are we doing?
Like a fairy tale
It's a sign the story has reached its end
Like a single passage taken from
A journey that was too long
Of the evil that once cast a shadow
Across this land
And the memories of the short journey
With the hero who defeated it
The story ends
And the hero goes to sleep
Leaving this land with
Days of peace and quiet
The passage of time heartlessly
Makes people forget
Even the tracks left behind by his life
Begin to rust
Just the same
Your words and wishes and courage
Are still inside of me
And they live on
We chose the same path
That's all it was supposed to be
Why is it that at some point
I wanted to understand the reason for
The tears that fall down my cheeks
Even now
If I retrace the journey we walked together
Even though you're not there
I know I'll be able to find it
Thank you.
With the road blocked,
I didn't know what I was going to do.
Hey, is this really necessary?
You're not happy about it?
The reward isn't bad.
No, I mean, couldn't you just use magic
to carry the cart to the other side?
That wouldn't help the
people who come after us.
That's what Fern said, anyway.
You're rather selfish, Stark.
That's rich, coming from you.
Thank you.
Hey, thanks.
By the way, why was there
a landslide in just this area?
The northern lands have been
fighting demons here and there, too.
This landslide was probably
caused by one such skirmish.
The scars of battle, huh?
Mr. Stark, could you take a break
from that to help me over here?
Mr. Stark?
Hey, could you stop calling me Mr. Stark?
It weirds me out.
We're not that different in age.
I see. Very well.
Stark, quit wasting time
and help me already. Hurry up.
So rude!
I meant more like, can't you speak to me
in a more casual or familiar way?
I see.
And can't you be friendlier, too?
I'm sensitive, okay?
What a pain in the rear.
What'd you call me?
Are you making progress over there?
Let's hurry, Mr. Stark.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
If you'd like, I can show you
the way to the town.
An elf, huh?
I've lived many years, but this
is my first time seeing one.
I suppose we're something of a rarity.
Come to think of it, I've never
seen an elf besides you.
There aren't very many of us.
I've only seen my own kind a handful of times.
Elves may live a long time,
but across the board, we lack romantic
feelings and reproductive instincts.
We're quietly going extinct.
The last time I met a fellow elf
was more than 400 years ago.
Perhaps we're closer
to the end than I thought.
We can see the town now.
There's a line of wagons.
Those look like merchants.
The Liberation Festival is tonight.
Today's the day Himmel
and his party of heroes
once defeated the demons who ruled this land.
Is that right?
That's what the Liberation
Festival commemorates.
The statues of Mr. Himmel and his companions
in the central plaza are decorated,
and the entire town
throws a grand celebration.
Humans love to make a fuss.
They hold festivals for everything.
It's been more than eighty years
since the demons were defeated.
That's more than enough time for something
to pass from human memory.
But on this day, everyone
remembers the party of heroes.
Nice work.
Five retakes, huh?
We finished sooner than usual this time.
You're always getting statues made, Himmel.
Because I want everyone to remember us.
Unlike you, we don't live that long.
I need future generations to
remember how handsome I was.
I'm heading back to the inn.
But I guess the biggest reason
is so you won't be alone in the future.
What does that mean?
We're not fairy tales.
We really existed.
Every year, we celebrate the great deeds
accomplished by the party of heroes.
Come to think of it, you look a lot
like the statue of Ms. Frieren
from that very party.
Will they still be doing this
a hundred years from now?
Yes, as long as this town still stands.
How about a thousand?
Well, I don't know.
Shall we go?
We're heading far to the north.
Come to think of it, you haven't
told me your destination yet.
Where are we going?
Heaven.
Now that sounds fun.
There are a lot of guards here.
Do you suppose something happened?
Let's decide who's going shopping.
Ms. Frieren, we're in a town.
I sense demons.
What?
Hey, you! What are you doing?
Graf Granat, did you put her up to this?
Lord Lügner, while it's true
I despise you and wish you dead,
I'm not foolish enough to openly attack
peace envoys in the middle of town.
Peace envoys?
They're probably adventurers
who don't know what's going on.
If you say so.
There's bloodlust in those calm, cold eyes.
Even the townsfolk who hate us
look upon me as a person,
even as they tremble in fear.
But you look at me as
though I'm a wild beast.
Aren't you?
You demons are wild beasts who
imitate human speech
but can't be communicated with.
Throw her in the dungeon
beneath the mansion.
Yes, milord.
Huh?
Hey!
I'm bored.
Ms. Frieren.
They said to reflect on your
actions for two or three years.
That's shorter than I expected.
Could you bring me some grimoires later?
You really do love to waste time.
I'm not here because I want to be.
So, what did he mean when he referred
to those demons as peace envoys?
I looked into it while shopping.
You know of Aura the Guillotine, don't you?
She's one of the Seven Sages of Destruction
who served the Demon King.
She lost most of her followers
fighting against us.
Last I heard, her whereabouts were unknown.
Did something happen recently?
Aura regained her power 28 years ago.
Her forces have been embroiled in battle
with this town for a long time,
but they've become exhausted
by the fruitless fighting,
so they're suing for peace.
So that's why they were allowed in as envoys.
That was a bad move.
Trying to talk to demons is pointless.
It can't be pointless.
They're capable of speech.
Surely the best option would be
to resolve things by talking them out?
They can't resolve things that way.
That's why it's pointless.
Demons are man-eating monsters.
Have you ever wondered why they
speak the same language as humans?
Hero, you must slay the fiend!
It's only a child.
So what? That thing ate our daughter!
It hurts...
It hurts, Mom...
Enough. I'll do it.
Then we'd be no different from the demons.
It's not as though they have to
eat humans to survive, right?
Why don't we give her
the opportunity to atone?
Chief...
You can't be serious!
Give us back our daughter!
I'll tend your wounds at my home.
I've been looking for someone
to help on the farm.
Himmel, you'll regret not
killing it now. It's a—
Frieren, we're capable of speech
with each other.
We'll be staying in this village anyway.
Why don't we see how it goes?
Fine.
Why did you kill the village chief?
We should've killed it back then.
There it is again.
Every day I felt your desire to kill me.
I just want to live in peace.
So I brought you a replacement
for the daughter I ate.
That's the village chief's daughter.
But the village chief is gone now.
It seems I've made a mistake somehow.
Then I have no choice.
I'm taking this child hostage.
You won't stop me again, will you?
No.
Mom...
"Mom" again?
Like monsters, demons don't raise their young.
They spend most of their time
after birth living in solitude.
You're solitary creatures by nature.
You have no concept of family.
So why do you use the word "mom"?
Because it stops you from killing us.
A wonderful, magical word...
For them, words are a means
of deceiving humans.
Flamme the Legendary Mage defined
monsters capable of speech as demons.
They're descended from
monsters who cried "help"
from the shadows to lure humans to them.
Don't forget to bring me grimoires.
Graf Granat is late.
A human diplomatic tactic.
In any case, I'm curious about that mage.
I know her face from somewhere.
Wild beasts who can't be
communicated with, huh?
That's an accurate description.
She's the only one in this town who
understands the true nature of us demons.
There's only one reason that predators
who prey on humans would
speak the human language.
They speak not to understand us
but to deceive us.
This town won't be around much longer.
I should take advantage of
the confusion to escape.
What is this?
My son's room.
He was a good boy.
He'd often boast about how he'd take over
the family soon so I could take it easy.
His Majesty gave him this sword
when he fought in his presence.
Where is your son now?
He died in battle against
Aura ten years ago.
All that came home to me was his sword.
Lügner!
I only invited you here to avenge my son.
I'm going to kill all of you
envoys here and now.
Your peace means nothing to me!
This room is quite clean.
I'm sure you've been keeping it
just as it was ten years ago.
So what if I have?
I've kept my father's room the same
since you killed him, too.
Why don't we put an end
to this, Graf Granat?
Or shall we continue to shed each other's
blood and cause even more grief?
We're capable of speech with each other.
Please grant us the opportunity
to settle this with discussion.
Show them to the guestroom.
I'll consider it.
Lord Lügner,
what is a "father"?
Who knows?
Graf Granat resents us, but he
seems to be an empathetic man.
If we win him over, we may
be able to convince him
to lower this town's defensive
barrier in the name of peace.
Then Lady Aura's forces will raze this town.
By the way, Linie, I don't see Draht.
He said he was off to eliminate an obstacle.
He's acting rashly.
What am I to do with that
hot-blooded youngster?
Lord Draht, you should not be here.
Please return to the guest—
Who are you? Visiting hours are over.
I am Draht, one of Aura the
Guillotine's executioners.
I am here to kill you.
I see. Done pretending to negotiate?
We're just getting started.
Uh-huh.
According to Lord Lügner,
this girl is the only obstacle in our way.
If I kill her, and we win over Graf Granat,
this town will fall easily.
Just so you know, I'm strong.
Stronger than me?
Stronger than Aura the Guillotine.
And you alright
Can you hear me
Trailing along deserted train tracks
Crying excessively
Wanting you to smile
I hold on to memories I'd like to keep fresh
There's something I'd like to tell you
With words more precious than a goodbye
Unremarkable yet special
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
So, if I were to be born again
I would surely choose this place once more
So, if we were to meet again
I'd never let you go, I'd choose the present
Even if no promises were made
Even if I'm lost in days of loneliness
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
for you to come back home
Who is that mage?
Speaking so casually to me
is a serious crime in this town...
We don't stand a chance against them.
You're a guard-killer who should be executed.
I hate fighting powerful opponents, too.
This fight is already over.
She slew more demons
than anyone else in history.